<resources>
    <string name="app_name">IFCO</string>

    <string name="drawer_open">Open</string>
    <string name="drawer_close">Close</string>

    <string name="nav_item_home">Home</string>
    <string name="nav_item_news">News</string>
    <string name="nav_item_guidelines">Guidelines</string>
    <string name="nav_item_what_we_do">What We Do</string>

    <string-array name="nav_drawer_labels">
        <item>@string/nav_item_home</item>
        <item>@string/nav_item_news</item>
        <item>@string/nav_item_guidelines</item>
        <item>@string/nav_item_what_we_do</item>
    </string-array>

    <string name="title_home">@string/nav_item_home</string>
    <string name="title_news">@string/nav_item_news</string>
    <string name="title_guidelines">@string/nav_item_guidelines</string>
    <string name="title_what_we_do">@string/nav_item_what_we_do</string>

    <dimen name="movie_title">17dp</dimen>

    <string name="survey_2015_title">FILM CLASSIFICATION SURVEY - PARENTAL ATTITUDES (POST PRIMARY) 2015</string>
    <string name="school_groups_title">SCHOOLS FOCUS GROUPS</string>
    <string name="survey_2013_title">2013 IFCO ANNUAL REPORT PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="survey_2012_title">2012 IFCO ANNUAL REPORT PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="survey_2011_title">2011 IFCO ANNUAL REPORT PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="survey_2010_title">2010 IFCO ANNUAL REPORT PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="survey_2009_title">2009 IFCO ANNUAL REPORT PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="survey_2008_title">2008 IFCO ANNUAL REPORT PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="survey_2007_title">2007 IFCO ANNUAL REPORT PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="survey_2006_title">2006 IFCO ANNUAL REPORT PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="survey_2005_title">2005 IFCO ANNUAL REPORT PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="survey_2004_title">2004 IFCO ANNUAL REPORT PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="parental_attitudes_title">FILM CLASSIFICATION SURVEY - PARENTAL ATTITUDES 2013</string>
    <string name="office_of_ombudsman_title">OFFICE OF THE OMBUDSMAN</string>
    <string name="office_of_ombudsman_children_title">OMBUDSMAN FOR CHILDREN\'S OFFICE</string>
    <string name="classification_young_kids_title">CLASSIFICATION FOR YOUNG KIDS</string>
    <string name="classification_guidelines_title">IFCO PUBLISHES NEW CLASSIFICATION GUIDELINES</string>
    <string name="minister_for_justice_title">MINISTER FOR JUSTICE, EQUALITY AND LAW REFORM LAUNCHES NEW IFCO ONLINE DVD CONSUMER ADVICE SERVICE FOR PARENTS</string>
    <string name="name_change_title">JULY 2008: NAME CHANGE AT IFCO</string>
    <string name="manhunt_game_title">MANHUNT 2 VIDEO GAME PROHIBITED</string>
    <string name="film_center_title">FILM CENSOR ANNOUNCES PUBLIC AWARENESS CAMPAIGN FOR FILM CLASSIFICATIONS</string>
    <string name="boy_eats_girl_title">APPEAL BOARD REVERSES FILM CENSOR\'S \'BOY EATS GIRL\' DECISION</string>
    <string name="happy_birthday_title">HAPPY BIRTHDAY!</string>
    <string name="changes_to_certs_title">FILM CENSOR ANNOUNCES CHANGES TO CINEMA FILM CERTIFICATES</string>
    <string name="adolescents_survey_title">FILM CENSOR PUBLISHES SURVEY OF ADOLESCENTS</string>
    <string name="parents_survey_title">FINDINGS OF NATIONAL PARENTS SURVEY PUBLISHED</string>
    <string name="website_launched_title">IFCO WEBSITE LAUNCHED</string>

    <string name="survey_2015_message">IFCO is pleased to publish the second part of our consultation with parents/guardians on their awareness of, and opinions on, the work undertaken by this Office. This work was carried out amongst parents/guardians of post-primary students and complements Parental Attitudes 2013 which surveyed the attitudes of parents of primary schoolchildren.\n\nOverseen by Assistant Classifier David Power, the results of IFCO\'s Parental Attitudes Survey 2015 are available here: Parental Attitudes (Post Primary) 2015\n\nFor further information please contact info@ifco.gov.ie</string>
    <string name="school_focus_group_message">As part of IFCO\’s on-going commitment to establishing a more complete picture of changes in perception and emphases among our consumer base, a series of focus groups/presentations were made in Irish schools throughout 2014. Carried out by our team of Assistant Classifiers, and designed by Classifiers David Power and Mark Brennan, these events focused on post-primary aged children and were invaluable in terms receiving firsthand feedback from children who our classifications are designed to protect.\n\nThe response from the schools that took part has been overwhelmingly positive and the feedback from the pupils will feed into the concluding part of our Attitudes survey to be published in the coming months.</string>
    <string name="parental_attitudes_message">As stated in the IFCO Annual Report 2012, following the updating of our classification guidelines, it was felt it was an opportune time to consult with consumers to gauge their awareness of, and opinions on, the work undertaken by this Office.\n\nOverseen by Assistant Classifiers David Power and Mark Brennan, the results of IFCO\'s Parental Attitudes Survey 2013 are available here: Parental Attitudes 2013\n\nFor further information please contact info@ifco.gov.ie</string>
    <string name="survey_2013_message">Click here to read or download the full report.\n\nCniog anseo chun an tuarascáil iomlán a fháil.</string>
    <string name="survey_2012_message">Click here to read or download the full report.\n\nCniog anseo chun an tuarascáil iomlán a fháil.</string>
    <string name="survey_2011_message">Click here to read or download the full report.\n\nCniog anseo chun an tuarascáil iomlán a fháil.</string>
    <string name="survey_2010_message">Click here to read or download the full report.\n\nCniog anseo chun an tuarascáil iomlán a fháil.</string>
    <string name="survey_2009_message">Click here to read or download the full report.\n\nCniog anseo chun an tuarascáil iomlán a fháil.</string>
    <string name="survey_2008_message">Click here to read or download the full report.\n\nCniog anseo chun an tuarascáil iomlán a fháil.</string>
    <string name="survey_2007_message">MRBI SURVEY FINDINGS PUBLISHED IN FILM CENSOR’S ANNUAL REPORT\n\nThe results of a national survey on attitudes to classification, carried out by MRBI for IFCO, (the Irish Film Censor\’s Office), are included in the Film Censor\’s Annual Report for 2007, which is published today (Thursday 29th May).\n\nThe survey sample consisted of 1,000 persons aged 15+ representative of the national population in terms of gender, age, social class and region.\n\nAmong the main findings of the survey, conducted via MRBI’s Phonebus,were:\n\n·	80% of respondents agreed with the Film Censor\’s decision to ban the video game Manhunt 2 on the grounds that its level of ‘gross, unrelenting and gratuitous violence was unacceptable’.\n\n·	85% would like to see IFCO\’s age ratings on films downloaded over the internet (even though respondents were advised this is currently outside IFCO\’s remit)\n\n·	72% said they would like to see IFCO\’s age ratings displayed before films shown on Irish television channels such as RTE and TV3.\n\n·	Asked which types of screen media they believe can have the most potentially negative effect on children, 44% of respondents said the internet, 32% video games, 17% television, 4% DVDs and 2% said cinema.\n\n·	Asked which film content might be considered most potentially harmful for children, 63% said violence, 21% drugs, 11% sex and 4% said language.\n\nIn his Report to the Minister for Justice, Equality and Law Reform, Mr. Dermot Ahern TD, the Film Censor, John Kelleher, noted that visitors to the IFCO website (which provides parents with user friendly consumer advice) had increased by 45% on the previous year. He pointed out, however, that this increase should be seen in the context of a disappointing response to another question in the MRBI survey, which showed that only 12% of respondents said they were aware of the IFCO website.\n\nSpeaking today on publication of his report, Mr. Kelleher said: “Our research shows that those parents who do use our website - www.ifco.ie - appreciate the consumer advice it provides. It will therefore be our main priority now to significantly increase the level of public awareness, particularly among parents.”\n\nIn 2007, almost 9,000 cinema films and DVDs were certified by IFCO.\n\nClick here to read or download the full report\n\nCniog anseo chun an tuarascáil iomlán a fháil.\n\nFor further information please contact Mark Brennan at mbrennan@ifco.gov.ie</string>
    <string name="survey_2006_message">The Film Censor, John Kelleher, has today (30th May 2007) published his Annual Report for the year 2006.\n\nClick here to see the Press Release\n\nAmong the key developments highlighted in the Report:\n\n·	More than 10,000 cinema films and DVD/videos were certified during the year.\n\n·	There was a significant increase in the number of non-mainstream or ‘arthouse’ films submitted for certification.\n\n·	The number of visitors to the IFCO website was up 16% on the previous year.\n\n·	The results of the research IFCO commissioned Lansdowne Market Research to carry out into the attitudes of parents and adolescents to strong language in films\n\nClick here to view or download the main findings\n\n·	The results of the research IFCO commissioned Dr. Jim Barratt, international film and media consultant, to carry out into future classification options in the fast changing landscape of film and home entertainment.\n\nClick here to view or download the main findings\n\n·	The launch by the Minister of Education and Science of the Pilot Review of the transition year module in moving image education at the IFI\n\nClick here to view or download the Pilot Review\n\nClick here to read or download the full Report\n\nCniog anseo chun an tuarascáil iomlán a fháil.</string>
    <string name="survey_2005_message">The Film Censor, John Kelleher, has published his Annual Report for the year 2005.\n\nAmong the key developments the Report highlights are:\n\n·	A significant increase in the total number video/DVDs classified.\n\n·	The publication of the findings of a major national survey entitled ‘Adolescents and Film: Attitudes to Film Classification’.\n\n·	The launch of our ongoing National Public Awareness Campaign which was carried out in cinemas, schools and through national media, with an aim to encourage parental responsibility and promote awareness of IFCO\’s certificates and guidelines.The Film Censor, John Kelleher, has today (30th May 2007) published his Annual Report for the year 2006.\n\nClick here to see the Press Release\n\nAmong the key developments highlighted in the Report:\n\n·	More than 10,000 cinema films and DVD/videos were certified during the year.\n\n·	There was a significant increase in the number of non-mainstream or ‘arthouse’ films submitted for certification.\n\n·	The number of visitors to the IFCO website was up 16% on the previous year.\n\n·	The results of the research IFCO commissioned Lansdowne Market Research to carry out into the attitudes of parents and adolescents to strong language in films\n\nClick here to view or download the main findings\n\n·	The results of the research IFCO commissioned Dr. Jim Barratt, international film and media consultant, to carry out into future classification options in the fast changing landscape of film and home entertainment.\n\nClick here to view or download the main findings\n\n·	The launch by the Minister of Education and Science of the Pilot Review of the transition year module in moving image education at the IFI\n\nClick here to view or download the Pilot Review\n\nClick here to read or download the full Report\n\nCniog anseo chun an tuarascáil iomlán a fháil.\n\nTo read the Report in full click here</string>
    <string name="survey_2004_message">The Film Censor, John Kelleher, has published his Annual Report for the year 2004.\n\nAmong the key developments the Report highlights are:\n\n·	A significant increase in the total number of films and video/DVDs certified\n\n·	An increase in the number of ‘art house’ films certified (low budget, foreign language, etc.)\n\n·	The introduction of a ‘16’ cinema certificate\n\n·	The launch of the IFCO website\n\n·	The publication of the Lansdowne Market Research parents survey\n\nTo read the Report in full click here</string>
    <string name="office_of_ombudsman_message">1st May 2013\n\nIf you feel you have been unfairly treated; or you are not satisfied with our decision on your complaint; it is open to you to contact the Office of the Ombudsman. By law the Office of the Ombudsman can examine complaints about everyday administrative activities as well as delays or inaction in dealings with us. The Office of the Ombudsman provides an impartial; independent and free complaints handling service.\n\nContact details are as follows:\nOffice of the Ombudsman\n18 Lower Leeson St\nDublin 2\nTel: 353 1 6395674\nE-mail: ombudsman@ombudsman.gov.ie\nWebsite: www.ombudsman.gov.ie</string>
    <string name="office_of_ombudsman_children_message">1st May 2013\n\nIf you are a child or young person under 18 or an adult who knows a child who you feel has been unfairly treated, or you are not satisfied with our decision on your complaint, it is open to you to contact the Ombudsman for Children\’s Office. By law the Ombudsman for Children\’s Office can investigate complaints about any of our administrative actions or procedures as well as delays or inaction in dealings with us. The Ombudsman for Children provides an impartial, independent and free complaints handling service.\n\nContact details are as follows:\nOmbudsman for Children\’s Office\n52-56 Great Strand St\nDublin 1\n\nFree Phone: 1800 20 20 40\nE-mail: ococomplaint@oco.ie\nWebsite: www.oco.ie</string>
    <string name="classification_young_kids_message">15th August 2012\n\nFilm Classifier David Power has written an article about film classification for young children for parenting website themotherload.ie.\n\nIn it he sets out exactly what the General Certificate means and how IFCO\'s website and newly published guidelines can assist parents in deciding what is appropriate viewing for their children.</string>
    <string name="classification_guidelines_message">2nd August 2012\n\nThe Irish Film Classification Office (IFCO) has published an updated and extended version of its Classification Guidelines to its website (www.ifco.ie). The newly published guidelines offer the public a greater insight into the work of the Office and cover both cinema and video (e.g., DVD, Blu Ray) releases.\n\nGer Connolly, Acting Director of Film Classification - The IFCO website is a resource for the public to research the suitability of cinema releases or video works for themselves and their families. These new guidelines offer parents/guardians a detailed breakdown of the differences in content between the age categories and will provide the public in general a clearer sense of how classification decisions are made.</string>
    <string name="minister_for_justice_message">On 21st July, 2009, the Minister for Justice, Equality and Law Reform, Dermot Ahern TD, visited IFCO\’s new offices in Smithfield, adjacent to the Light House Cinema, where he launched IFCO\’s new online DVD consumer advice service for parents.\n\nThe new service provides parents and the public with the same kind of welcome consumer information and advice for DVD releases that IFCO already provides online for films.\n\nMinister Ahern said: “IFCO\’s new office environment, and its innovative Public Private Partnership with the Light House Cinema, perfectly reflects how the Irish Film Classification Office – 86 years in existence - has embraced change, openness and modernisation in recent years.\n\n“This new service puts parents in the driving seat, providing them with valuable information via www.ifco.ie on the age-related classification of every new DVD that is released on the Irish market.”\n\nIFCO Director, John Kelleher, added: “This new service also enables IFCO\’s commercial customers to transact their business online. It\’s an initiative that has made IFCO\’s service comparable or superior to similar organisations worldwide, and has been warmly welcomed by the industry.”.\n\nClick here to read or download the press release.</string>
    <string name="name_change_message">With effect from today 20th July 2008, the Civil Law (Miscellaneous Provisions) Act 2008 has amended some sections of the 1923 Censorship of Films Act and the 1989 Video Recordings Act as follows:\n\n·	The Irish Film Censor\’s Office becomes the Irish Film Classification Office and the Official Film Censor will now be known as the Director of Film Classification.\n\n·	The phrase “likely to cause harm to children” is introduced into the legislation for the first time.\n\n·	Lower fees will be charged for classifying specialty interest DVDs. This initiative is similar to the highly successful ‘limited release initiative’ for cinema films, which was introduced in 2004.\n\n·	It will now be an offence to supply a DVD to a person who is under the IFCO-designated age rating.\n\n·	Fines for certain offences are updated.\n\nWelcoming the changes and IFCO\n’s modernized remit as an open and transparent agency, the Minister said: ‘The role of the Film Censor has evolved to reflect changed times. In a mature society, I think most of us believe that adults should be free (subject to the law) to decide for themselves what they may see, and the primary role for IFCO should be what we call age-related classification’.\n\nThe Director of Film Classification said: “Today, we don\’t censor, we classify. We don\’t decline to explain or justify our decisions. Rather, we welcome the fact that we can provide the public, and parents in particular, with age-related classification and consumer advice. We have gone from stop sign to sign post. This is a very special occasion for all of us here at Harcourt Terrace. For me, on both a professional and personal basis, it\’s a really special and symbolic day.\n\nAmong those attending were were former Film Censor, Sheamus Smith, Dr. Kevin Rockett of TCD, author of ‘Irish Film Censorship’, Ciarán Carty (longtime campaigner for liberalising censorship laws), Terry Molloy from Warners, Barbara Murphy from Sony Pictures, Trish Long from Disney, Siobhan Farrell from Eclipse Pictures, Niamh McCaul and Seamus O’Toole from Paramount, Arthur McGuinness from Dublin Film Distributors, Paul Ward from the Ward Anderson group, Irish Times film critic, Michael Dwyer and Ted Sheehy of Screen International.\n\nFor further information please contact Mark Brennan at mbrennan@ifco.gov.ie</string>
    <string name="manhunt_message">A prohibition order has been made by IFCO in relation to the video game Manhunt 2. The Order was made on 18th June 2007 under Sec 7 (1) (b) of the Video Recordings Act 1989 which refers to ‘acts of gross violence or cruelty (including mutilation and torture)’.\n\nIFCO recognizes that in certain films, DVDs and video games, strong graphic violence may be a justifiable element within the overall context of the work. However, in the case of Manhunt 2, IFCO believes that there is no such context, and the level of gross, unrelenting and gratuitous violence is unacceptable.</string>
    <string name="film_censor_message">On Tuesday November 15th, the Minister for Justice, Equality and Law Reform, Mr. Michael McDowell, launched the Film Censor\’s cinema and media campaign to inform the public about IFCO\’s current film certificates, classification guidelines and website which provides information and consumer advice for parents.\n\nThe campaign, which is timed to coincide with the imminent nationwide release of several of the most eagerly anticipated films of the year, including Harry Potter and The Goblet of Fire, The Chronicles of Narnia, King Kong and The Producers, involves a number of initiatives:\n\nOne million wallet-sized booklets, entitled ‘Your Pocket Guide to Film Classification’, will be presented to the cinema-going public and will also be distributed with all copies of the RTE Guide. The Pocket Guide explains the IFCO certs in detail and includes typical examples for each classification.\n\nThe existing Film Censor certificate which is displayed in cinemas before each film will be replaced by a new animated film cert, which has been directed by Zachary Harpur and produced by the Oscar-nominated Irish company, Brown Bag Films (Give Up Yer Aul Sins). The new certificate specifically draws attention to the IFCO website.\n\nSpecially designed posters and stickers, which describe the IFCO certificates and highlight the website, will be displayed in all cinema foyers and at ticket desks.\n\nAn IFCO Assistant Censor, Ms. Dani McClafferty, has been appointed as cinema liaison officer and will be in day-to-day contact with cinema managers all over Ireland as well as the cinema-going public.\n\nCommenting on the initiative, Film Censor Mr John Kelleher said: “The primary aim of the awareness campaign is to attract the public and parents in particular to visit our website in increasing numbers. This Office strongly encourages and promotes parental responsibility, recognising that it is parents who know their own children best. In that regard, a key function of the IFCO website is to facilitate parents by providing them with specific consumer advice about individual films as well as general information about our guidelines and classification policies”.\n\nThe Irish Film Censor\’s Office, a statutory agency that has existed since 1923, is responsible for examining and certifying all films and video/DVDs distributed in Ireland. IFCO has experienced a radical modernising overhaul in recent years as it moves from its earlier ‘gatekeeper’ role to become an agency that classifies on an age-related basis, a consumer advice oriented organisation that aims to inform the public and parents, rather than to restrict information, and to encourage the intelligent enjoyment of film by the most avid cinema-going nation in Europe. Last year IFCO classified 610 cinema films (including trailers) and over 7,500 video/DVDs.</string>
    <string name="boy_eats_girl_message">Abbey Films, the distributor of the Irish film ‘Boy Eats Girl’ has succeeded in its appeal against a decision of the Film Censor.\n\nOn 25th July, the Censorship of Films Appeal Board reversed the Film Censor\’s decision to withhold a certificate to the Irish film ‘Boy Eats Girl’ unless a designated scene (depicting an ostensible suicide attempt) was cut. The Appeal Board\’s decision was unanimous.\n\n‘Boy Eats Girl’, produced by Element Films, will be released on the 23rd of September with a 15A certificate.</string>
    <string name="happy_birthday_message">The IFCO website, which was launched by the Minister for Justice, Equality and Law Reform, Michael McDowell, TD, on 5th September 2004, is now one year old.\n\nI would like to take this opportunity to thank all of you who have visited the site during the year. We hope the information we provide is useful - especially to parents. Do please let us know if you have any suggestions as to how to improve the site. Your feedback is most welcome.\n\nBest wishes\nJohn Kelleher\nFilm Censor</string>
    <string name="changes_to_certs_message">Changes to Cinema Film Certificates\n\nTwo changes to the existing film certificate categories are announced today (December 9th, 2004) by the Film Censor, John Kelleher, which will take effect from 1st January 2005.\n\n·	A new ‘16’ certificate will be introduced. Where films carry this certificate admission will be restricted to persons aged sixteen and over.\n\n·	The existing ‘12PG’ and ‘15PG’ certificates will be re-designated ‘12A’ and ‘15A’, where the ‘A’ denotes adult.\n\nThese changes have been made following consultations with parents, educators, the public, film distributors and cinema managers. They also take account of findings of the nationwide survey of parents published last September, which was carried out for Irish Film Censor\’s Office (IFCO) by Lansdowne Market Research. The results of a further national survey, this time of more than a thousand adolescents, will be published early in the New Year.\n\nVideo classifications remain the same.\n\nThe full cinema certification categories are now as follows:\n\n·	GENERAL: Suitable for all ages.\n\n·	PG: Suitable for all ages, but parental guidance advised.\n\n·	12A: Films in this category are, in the opinion of the Film Censor, suitable for those aged 12 and over only. However, children under that age will be admitted if accompanied by an adult.\n\n·	15A: Films in this category are, in the opinion of the Film Censor, suitable for those aged 15 and over only. However, children under that age will be admitted if accompanied by an adult.\n\n·	16: Admission is restricted to persons aged sixteen and over.\n\n·	18: Admission is restricted to persons aged eighteen and over.\n\nParents are strongly recommended to consult the IFCO website www.ifco.ie for general classification guidelines and consumer information on individual films.</string>
    <string name="adolescent_survey_message">The findings of a major nationwide survey of adolescent attitudes to film classification was published this month (March 2005) by IFCO, the Irish Film Censor\’s Office.\n\n1,045 adolescents, aged between twelve and seventeen, were surveyed at twelve schools randomly selected to provide a representative national sample.\n\nThe survey was jointly carried out for IFCO by the School of Communications, DCU and the School of Business Studies and Humanities, IADT, Dun Laoghaire, under the supervision of Dr. Carol MacKeogh.\n\nThis is the second stage of a major research project into attitudes to film classification commissioned by the Film Censor. The first stage, the first ever national survey of parents, was carried out for IFCO by Lansdowne Market Research and was published in September 2004.\n\nclick here for survey results</string>
    <string name="parent_survey_message">The results of the first ever national survey of parents on issues relating to their children\’s viewing of films and video/DVDs were published on Friday 3rd September by IFCO and can shortly be seen on IFCO\’s new website which was launched simultaneously.\n\nThe primary aim of the survey, which was carried out for IFCO by Lansdowne Market Research, was to identify the main areas of interest to parents in relation to film and video content and classification. Lansdowne surveyed over 250 parents of children attending 12 post-primary schools, randomly selected to provide a representative sample in terms of area, socio-economic, gender and religious composition.\n\nclick here for survey results\n\nIn October, the second phase of IFCO\’s research project, undertaken jointly by DCU and the IADT in Dun Laoghaire, under the supervision of Dr. Carol MacKeogh, will report on adolescents\’ perspective on film classification.</string>
    <string name="website_launched_message">IFCO\’s new website went live on Friday 3rd September.\n\nSpeaking at the launch, which was attended by the Minister for Justice, Equality and Law Reform, the Film Censor, John Kelleher, said the website had a dual purpose. It would give the public an idea of what IFCO does as well as provide parents with relevant information about individual films and video/DVDs.\n\n“We strongly encourage and promote the exercise of parental responsibility”, Mr. Kelleher said, “and I am confident that the IFCO website will help to give parents the kind of information that will help to inform their decisions.</string>

    <string name="guidelines_introduction">Our approach to classifying cinema releases and video works (e.g., DVD, BluRay) is guided by three main principles:\n\nWe believe that adults (i.e., persons over 18) should be free, within the law, to choose what they wish to view.\n\nWe have a duty to protect children and young people from harm.\n\nWe strongly encourage and promote the exercise of parental responsibility.\n</string>
    <string name="guidelines_classifications">The Irish Film Classification Office (IFCO) website is primarily a resource for the public, and for parents/guardians in particular, to research the suitability of cinema releases or video works for themselves or their families. We strongly encourage that parents/guardians make informed decisions, using not just the age classification awarded but also the detailed consumer advice available on this website and through the various links provided.\n</string>
    <string name="guidelines_context">It is important to note that the context in which material is presented in a film will often be the determining factor in the age classification it is awarded. Where certain material is presented in a fantasy or comic context, for example, its impact may be softened. We try to retain a flexibility of approach and look at the context and impact of the film as a whole, rather than rating it only on the basis of one short image or scene - i.e., consideration is given as to whether content is presented within an educational context, either social (e.g., anti-drugs, anti-discrimination) or historical.\n</string>
    <string name="guidelines">The role of IFCO was established under the Censorship of Films Act, 1923 and expanded upon in the Video Recordings Act, 1989. This legislation is framed so as to allow IFCO reflect the prevailing social values of the day. IFCO actively welcomes feedback from parents and the public concerning its classification guidelines and decisions.\n\nTo get in touch, please contact info@ifco.gov.ie\n</string>

    <string name="certificate_title_18">18 Certificate - Guidelines</string>
    <string name="certificate_title_16">16 Certificate - Guidelines</string>
    <string name="certificate_title_15A">15A Certificate - Guidelines</string>
    <string name="certificate_title_12A">12A Certificate - Guidelines</string>
    <string name="certificate_title_PG">PG Certificate - Guidelines</string>
    <string name="certificate_title_G">General Certificate - Guidelines</string>

    <string name="cert_film_18_introduction">Films classified in this category are suitable for persons of eighteen or over. Those under eighteen will not be admitted to cinemas and it is the responsibility of each cinema, under law, to ensure that this is the case.\n\nOne of IFCO’s guiding principles is that adults (i.e., persons over 18) should be free, within the law, to choose what they wish to view.\n\nThe IFCO website provides consumer advice on films rated in this category as practical information regarding film content is appreciated by the cinema-going public.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_16_introduction">Films classified in this category are suitable for persons of sixteen or over. Those under sixteen will not be admitted to cinemas and it is the responsibility of each cinema, under law, to ensure that this is the case.\n\nThe 16 certificate recognizes the ability of today’s teenagers to digest and understand mature themes and complex material. Many films that would previously have been classified 18 are now classified in this category.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_15A_introduction">Films classified 15A have been deemed appropriate for viewers of fifteen and over. However, they can also be seen by younger children - provided they are accompanied by an adult who has deemed the film appropriate viewing for that child. In such cases, IFCO strongly recommends that parents/guardians make informed decisions by accessing the consumer advice available on this website.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_12A_introduction">Films classified 12A have been deemed appropriate for viewers of twelve and over. However, they can also be seen by younger children - provided they are accompanied by an adult who has deemed the film appropriate viewing for that child. In such cases, IFCO strongly recommends that parents/guardians make informed decisions by accessing the consumer advice available on this website.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_PG_introduction">Generally, a film classified as ‘PG’ will be suitable for children aged eight and over. However, as some elements within the film might be unsettling for some viewers, it is strongly recommended that parents/guardians - who know their own children best - consult the consumer advice available on this website before deciding on what is appropriate.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_G_introduction">A film classified as ‘General’ should be suitable for children of a school going age. However, as not every child will respond in the same way to particular themes, scenes and images, it is strongly recommended that parents/guardians - who know their own children best - consult the consumer advice available on this website before deciding what is appropriate.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_film_16_theme">Most themes/content will be acceptable with classification decided by the way the subject is treated.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_15A_theme">Most themes/content will be acceptable with classification decided by the way the subject is treated.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_12A_theme">Mature themes are acceptable (crime, bereavement, relationships, etc.) provided they are depicted in a fashion suitable for young teenagers (i.e., in such a way that they will already have been familiar with in their everyday lives). Themes of suicide or self-harm or other imitable behaviour will only be acceptable if depicted without detail and in a clearly educational context.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_PG_theme">A Parental Guidance certificate does not necessarily signify a ‘children’s picture’, but while more mature issues might be addressed (e.g., war, family issues) there will generally be a positive or redemptive resolution.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_G_theme">While a General certificate does not necessarily signify a ‘children’s picture’, such films will not include themes or content that will upset younger children.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_film_16_violence">Violence might be intensely depicted and may include some gory imagery. We take particular account of the way in which sexual violence is portrayed. The portrayal of such content in this category should not be explicit and must have clear contextual justification.\n\nStrong horror and sustained threat may be acceptable but will not include the strongest images of sadism and torture.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_15A_violence">Violence may be realistic but not gratuitous or focus on bloody injury. Strong gory images will only be permitted if justified by the context in which they are presented. We take particular account of the way in which sexual violence is portrayed. Any such content in this category should be discreetly presented and contextually justified. Generally, horror in this category will be psychological in nature. Acts of sadism common to the genre are not permissible.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_12A_violence">Moderate violence and more prolonged threat/horror are acceptable at 12A. This is particularly the case when depicted in a fantasy context (common at this category). Stronger images of injury detail may be acceptable if justified by the context in which they are presented (i.e., in an accurate depiction of warfare).\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_PG_violence">Any frightening sequences should not be sustained or graphic. However, some stronger violence may be permissible in what is clearly a fantasy or comic context.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_G_violence">Children can cope with and enjoy some frightening content in the films they view (e.g., fairytale villains). A General certificate film may include such content but these sequences will be mild and unsustained, there will be an absence of blood or injury detail and any outcome will be reassuring.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_film_16_sexual_content">Strong sexual themes and content may be permissible provided it is not gratuitous.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_15A_sexual_content">Strong sex references may be acceptable at 15A. Scenes of a sexual nature may also be acceptable but will not be explicit or prolonged.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_12A_sexual_content">Sexual content (situations and dialogue) presented without explicit detail may be acceptable at 12A. Brief sexual nudity may also be acceptable.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_PG_sexual_content">Sex references will be mild and any sexual activity will be implied rather than depicted. Subtle innuendo may be accepted.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_G_sexual_content">If present, such content will be very mild (e.g., kissing, dating, references to ‘making love’). In certain circumstances, non-sexual nudity may be acceptable.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_film_16_language">Strong language is acceptable within this category.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_15A_language">Strong language is allowed at 15A. Frequent or aggressive use of these terms will have to be justified within the context of the piece.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_12A_language">Some infrequent strong language may be acceptable, but should be used in a non-aggressive manner. Use of discriminatory language should be justified by the overall context of the film.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_PG_language">The language will be mild. However, in rare instances, a PG film may contain infrequent strong language provided it is used discreetly and is contextually justified. Discriminatory or racist terms will only be acceptable if used in a clearly educational context.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_G_language">General certificate films may include infrequent use of mild bad language and slang.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_film_16_drugs">Films at this category might feature themes and scenes relating to hard drug use. However, any instructional or glamorised drug use, particularly involving teen protagonists, is unlikely to be acceptable.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_15A_drugs">Scenes or dialogue relating to drugs may be acceptable in an appropriate context, but not if there is glamorization, instruction or encouragement as to use.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_12A_drugs">Images of or references to soft drugs may be permitted in an appropriate context. Generally, content relating to hard drugs is not acceptable unless there is a clear anti-drug message and the misuse of drugs is not glamorized.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_PG_drugs">Any references to drug use should be mild and will relate to soft drug use only. Where stronger references are made they will be set within a clearly educational context.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_G_drugs">There will be no drug use or drug references unless clearly set within an educational context.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_film_16_note">Some films released on DVD with a 15 cert may have a cinema release certificate 16 due to the difference in cinema/DVD classification structure. It is illegal for a retailer to sell or rent a film classified 15 to any person below that age.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_film_15A_note">Some films released on DVD with a 15 cert may have a cinema release certificate 16 due to the difference in cinema/DVD classification structure. It is illegal for a retailer to sell or rent a film classified 15 to any person below that age.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_dvd_18_introduction">Fit for viewing by persons aged 18 YEARS OR MORE.\n\nOiriúnach lena bhreathnú ag daoine atá 18 mbliana d\'aois nó os a chionn.\n\nVideo works classified in this category are suitable for persons of eighteen or over. It is an offence for a retailer to sell or rent a film classified 18 to any person below that age.\n\nOne of IFCO’s guiding principles is that adults (i.e., persons over 18) should be free, within the law, to choose what they wish to view.\n\nThe IFCO website provides consumer advice on films rated in this category as practical information regarding film content is appreciated by the cinema-going public.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_15_introduction">Fit for viewing by persons aged 15 YEARS OR MORE.\n\nOiriúnach lena bhreathnú ag daoine atá 15 bliana d\'aois nó os a chionn.\n\nVideo works classified 15 have been deemed appropriate for viewers of fifteen and over. It is offence for a retailer to sell or rent material classified 15 to anyone below that age.\n\nGenerally, films classified 16 on cinema release will be classified 15 on video release (e.g., ‘Cabin In The Woods’, ‘A Dangerous Method’, ‘Headhunters’).\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_12_introduction">Fit for viewing by persons aged 12 YEARS OR MORE.\n\nOiriúnach lena bhreathnú ag daoine atá 12 bhliain d\'aois nó os a chionn.\n\nVideo works classified 12 have been deemed appropriate for viewers of twelve and over. It is offence for a retailer to sell or rent material classified 12 to anyone below that age.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_PG_introduction">Fit for viewing generally, but in the case of a child under 12 years, under PARENTAL GUIDANCE.\n\nOiriúnach lena bhreathnú ag daoine i gcoitinne ach, i gcás linbh faoi bhun 12 bhliain d\'aois, faoi Threoir Tuismitheora.\n\nGenerally, video works classified as ‘PG’ will be suitable for children aged eight and over. However, as some elements within the work might be unsettling for some viewers, it is strongly recommended that parents/guardians - who know their own children best - consult the consumer advice available on this website before deciding on what is appropriate.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_G_introduction">Fit for viewing by persons generally.\n\nOiriúnach lena bhreathnú ag daoine i gcoitinne.\n\nA video work classified as ‘General’ should be suitable for children of a school going age. However, as not every child will respond in the same way to particular themes, scenes and images, it is strongly recommended that parents/guardians - who know their own children best - consult the consumer advice available on this website before deciding what is appropriate.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_dvd_15_theme">Most themes/content will be acceptable with classification decided by the way the subject is treated.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_12_theme">Mature themes are acceptable (crime, bereavement, relationships, etc.) provided they are depicted in a fashion suitable for young teenagers (i.e., in such a way that they will already have been familiar with in their everyday lives). Themes of suicide or self-harm or other imitable behaviour will only be acceptable if depicted without detail and in a clearly educational context.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_PG_theme">A Parental Guidance certificate does not necessarily signify a ‘children’s picture’, but while more mature issues might be addressed (e.g., war, family issues) there will generally be a positive or redemptive resolution.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_G_theme">While a General certificate does not necessarily signify a ‘children’s picture’, such films will not include themes or content that will upset younger children.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_dvd_15_violence">Violence may be realistic but not gratuitous or focus on bloody injury. Strong gory images will only be permitted if justified by the context in which they are presented. We take particular account of the way in which sexual violence is portrayed. Any such content in this category should be discreetly presented and contextually justified.\n\nStrong horror and threat are acceptable but will not include the strongest images of sadism and torture.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_12_violence">Moderate violence and more prolonged threat/horror are acceptable at 12. This is particularly the case when depicted in a fantasy context (common at this category). Stronger images of injury detail may be acceptable if justified by the context in which they are presented (i.e., in an accurate depiction of warfare).\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_PG_violence">Any frightening sequences should not be sustained or graphic. However, some stronger violence may be permissible in what is clearly a fantasy or comic context.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_G_violence">Children can cope with and enjoy some frightening content in the films they view (e.g., fairytale villains). A General certificate film may include such content but these sequences will be mild and unsustained, there will be an absence of blood or injury detail and any outcome will be reassuring.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_dvd_15_sexual_content">Strong sex references may be acceptable at 15. Scenes of a sexual nature may also be acceptable but will not gratuitous or prolonged.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_12_sexual_content">Sexual content (situations and dialogue) presented without explicit detail may be acceptable at 12. Brief sexual nudity may also be acceptable.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_PG_sexual_content">Sex references will be mild and any sexual activity will be implied rather than depicted. Subtle innuendo may be accepted.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_G_sexual_content">If present, such content will be very mild (e.g., kissing, dating, references to ‘making love’). In certain circumstances, non-sexual nudity may be acceptable.\n</string>

    <string name="cert_dvd_15_language">Strong language is allowed at 15.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_12_language">Some infrequent strong language may be acceptable, but should be used in a non-aggressive manner. Use of discriminatory language should be justified by the overall context of the film.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_PG_language">The language will be mild. However, in rare instances, a PG film may contain infrequent strong language provided it is used discreetly and is contextually justified. Discriminatory or racist terms will only be acceptable if used in a clearly educational context.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_G_language">General certificate films may include infrequent use of mild bad language and slang\n</string>

    <string name="cert_dvd_15_drugs">Scenes or dialogue relating to drugs may be acceptable in an appropriate context, but not if there is glamorization, instruction or encouragement as to use.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_12_drugs">mages of or references to soft drugs may be permitted in an appropriate context. Generally, content relating to hard drugs is not acceptable unless there is a clear anti-drug message and the misuse of drugs is not glamorized.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_PG_drugs">Any references to drug use should be mild and will relate to soft drug use only. Where stronger references are made they will be set within a clearly educational context.\n</string>
    <string name="cert_dvd_G_drugs">There will be no drug use or drug references unless clearly set within an educational context.\n</string>

    <string name="what_we_do">IFCO, a statutory body first established in 1923, is responsible for examining and certifying all cinema films and videos/DVDs distributed in Ireland.\n\nOur aim is to provide the public and parents in particular with a modern and dependable system of classification that:\n\nProtects children and young persons\nHas regard for freedom of expression\nHas respect for the values of Irish society\n\nIn 2013, IFCO classified 768 cinema works (including trailers) and 4336 video works.\n\nFor further information on how we operate, check out our 2013 Annual Report</string>
</resources>
